Guide to the Walter Bordwell Papers, 1835-1929 (inclusive), 1890-1912 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
Walter Bordwell Papers,
1835-1929 (inclusive), 1890-1912 (bulk)
Special Collections M0256
Bordwell, Walter
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Walter B. Lull, 1976.
Scope and Content
The Judge Walter Bordwell Papers concern both his private and professional life as lawyer and judge. The collection spans the years 1835-1929, with the bulk of the material occurring from 1890-1912, during which his career was most active. There is little material from 1915-1925 - the years betwen his retiring as Los Angeles Superior Court Judge and his death. The material is grouped and arranged generally, but not strictly, in alphabetical order. Items within the groups are arranged chronologically but with attached items left attached.
The first half of the collection (boxes 1-4) deals with his personnal holdings. Included are diaries, memorandum books, financial records and receipts, business cards, a Bible, and a 1928-29 edition of Whos's Who in California, in which is a biographical sketch of Bordwell. There is little personal correspondence, most of which is between him and his cousin Charles Bordwell during the years 1897-1902. There is no original photograph of Judge Bordwell; there are, however, several articles with pictures of him dispersed throughout the newspaper clippings.
Material from his professional life is contained in the second half of the collection (boxes 5-8). Included are his certificates to practice law, correspondence, pamphlets, dockets, lists, handwritten drafts, and marriage contracts. His most publicized case within the collection is the McNamara Brothers - Burning of the L.A. Times Building Investigation. Although few of the actual court proceedings for this trial are included, there is a variety of correspondence from the public to the Judge, newspaper clippings, and a journal kept by the Judge during the trial. Much information is also contained on the Helena M. Granger vs. Henry W. Robinson case.
Included within the bulk of newspapers are a considerable number of clippings on World War II events.
Notable correspondents and others involved with his cases include Clarence Darrow, Governor James Hawley of Idaho, and U.S Senator John D. Works.
Index of Names (Box - Folder)
Bernard, Obed (Box 6)
Bordwell, Charles (2-12)
Bordwell, Eliza (2-12)
Bordwell, George (2-4)
Bordwell, J. L. (5-10)
Bordwell, Mrs. Walter, (2-2, 2-6)
Bordwell, Midad (?) (2-11)
Chubb, Amand (5-17)
Darrow, Clarence (Box 7)
Diehm, Ferdinand (5-1)
Dunbar, E.G.B. (5-9)
Folsom, E.W. (5-10)
German American Savings Bank (2-4, 2-11, 5-11, 5-15)
Granger, Helena M. (Box 6)
Habl, Ferdinand (5-11)
Harriman, Job (7-4)
Hawley, Governor James (5-13)
Ingersoll, George (2-12, 5-2, 5-16)
McDonald, E.N. (5-14, 5-15)
McNamara, J.J. & J.B. (Box 7)
McNamara, John A. (7-2)
Nightingale, Newell (5-16)
Palmer, F.E. (5-17)
Penn, William (2-4)
Robinson, Henry W. (Box 6)
Robinson, Eliza A. (Box 6)
Satterwhite, Thomas D. (5-10)
Stohr, Silvester (5-11)
Windsor, Herbert E. (2-2, 5-7, 5-2)
Winternitz, J.U. Dr. Oscar Winternitz (5-12)
Works, Senator John D. (5-13)
Container List
- Bible, King James Edition (upon which the oath of office was administered to Hon. Edwin Willists, the first Assistant Secretary of Agriculture in the U.S.) (Othertype 1)
- Business cards. (Othertype 1)
- Diaries (Othertype 1)
  - 1893
  - 1894
  - 1895
  - 1896
  - 1897
  - 1898
  - 1899
  - 1900
  - 1901
  - 1902
  - 1903
  - 1904
  - 1905
- Memoradum Books (Othertype 1)
  - 1892
  - 1892-93
  - 1892-95
  - 1894
  - 1896
- Who's Who in California, 1928-29edition. (Othertype 1)
  Autographed by editor and personalized with Walter Bordwell's name. Biographical sketch of Bordwell on p.433.
- Misc. Personnel (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - postcard of L.A courthouse
  - photograph
- Misc. Postcards (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - July 3, 1891. -H.E.W. to Walter Bordwell (Marshall, Mich.)
  - Aug. 7, 1895. -?to Walter Bordwell (San Bernardino)
  - ND -William Wilson Company (L.A.)
- May 4, 1916. -?to Mrs. Walter Bordwell (San Diego)
- Dec. 18, 1897 -(cousin) Charles M. Bordwell to W.B. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dec. 24, 1897 -W.B. to CMB
- Dec. 30, 1897-July 10, 1902.14 letters to W.B. from CMB.
- Jan. 18, 1898 -W.B. to Mr. W.H. Penn, chief clerk, Des Moines, IA.
- April 1, 1905. -Telegraph from L.A. National Bank to Corn Exchange National Bank.
- Apr. 22, 1912. -Alexander Tison to W.B.
- Apr. 24, 1912. -Francis Heney, Attorney to W.B.
- Apr. 30, 1912. -W.B. to Francis Heney
- Jun. 1, 1912. -W.B. to Alexander Tison
- July 9, 1912. -Albert Searl to W.B.
- July 16, 1912. -C. Foster Cable to W.B. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- July 19, 1912. -W.B. to Albert Searl
- July 19, 1912. -Fred Taft to W.B.
- July 19, 1912. -Fred Taft to editor of L.A. Times Tribune
- July 19, 1912. -W.B. to Foster Cable
- July 20, 1912. -W.B. to Fred Taft
- Sept. 15, 1912. -Lucien Shaw, Asst. Justice, to W.B. w/encl
- Oct. 29, 1912 -George Bordwell (brother) to W.B.
- Nov. 9, 1912 -W.B. to George Bordwell
- Nov. 13, 1912 -Alexander Tison to W.B.
- Jan.10, 1913 -Chas. S. Brown, Mgr. steamship dept., German American Savings Bank to North German Lloyd Steamship Co.
- Misc. Bills and Receipts (belonging to W.B. unless otherwise noted) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Feb. 19, 1887 -Contract with Home Telephone Company
  - Aug. 14, 1893 -bill from Home Telephone & Telegraph Co.
  - June 6, 1912 -Contract of subscription with the Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Co.
  - June 6, 1912 -receipt from Pacific T&T
  - Dec. 24, 1912 -statement from Peter T. Anderson (Tailor)
  - Jan. 1, 1913 -statement from Dr. Edward E. Kaisor (Dental Surgeon)
  - Jan. 3, 1913 -receipt from Redondo Floral Co.
  - Jan. 4, 1913 -statement from Peter T. Anderson
  - Jan. 7, 1913 -statement from California Electric Co.
  - June 1913 -receipt from Couldress Dry Goods Co.
  - Aug. 1, 1913 -special receipt from Home T&T Co.
  - Aug. 2, 1913 -contract for extension telephone from the Pacific T&t Co.
  - Aug. 2, 1913-contract of subscription from the Pacific T&T Co.
  - Sept. 1, 1933-statement from Newberry Electric Corp.
- Inventory of Home, Jan. 22, 1913-Waldo Fallcon to Mary E. Bordwell (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Clubs and Organizations (receipts, correspondence, misc.) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Municipal Club of L.A. - dues receipt, July 1, 1913
  - California Club (L.A.)- member to W.B., May 22, 1912
  - California Club- member to W.B., Nov. 8, 1912
  - California Club-dinner bill, Apr. 16, 1913
  - California Club-dues bill, June 1, 1913
  - California Club-dues bill, July 1, 1913
  - Gamut Club (L.A.)-receipt of dues, Jan 1, 1913
  - L.A. Tent No.2, Knights of the Macabees- receipts, monthly, June 1891-Nov. 1898, June, 1913, July, 1913
  - K.O.T.M.- Endowment certificate, July 8, 1891
  - K.O.T.M.- receipt book, Dec. 21, 1892-Dec..31, 1907
  - K.O.T.M.- receipt book, Jan 27, 1908-Dec. 31, 1912
  - K.O.T.M.- E.M. Guthrie, record keeper, to W.B., Jan. 6, 1905
- Misc. Business Dealings (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Northwestern Masonic Aid Association - receipt of payment; June 20, 1891.
  - Northwestern MAA - certificate of membership; Aug. 4, 1892
  - Northwestern MAA - Notices of assessment; every other month Aug. 1, 1891-Aug 1, 1900
- Insurance Statements and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Morengo Village Cemetary Assocation - receipt of payment; May 13, 1911
  - Title Insurance and Trust Company - escrow receipt; Aug. 17, 1911
  - U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Company - continuation Aug. 17, 1902
  - U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Company - continuation 1903
  - U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Company - continuation 1905
  - U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Co-guaranty bonds; 1901-1902
  - U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Co-guaranty bonds; 1905-1906
  - Mutual Reserve Life Insurance (Chicago) - Letter to WB, May 10, 1904
  - re MRLI - Louis Vetter, Agent of Employers' Liability Assurance Corp. to WB, Feb 5, 1905
  - MRLI to WB, Oct. 12, 1906
  - MRLI to WB, May 26, 1907
  - MRLI to WB, ND
  - re MRLI - Clark Varnum, att, to WB, Oct. 1, 1907
  - re MRLI - WB to Mr. Clark Varnum, att; Oct. 7, 1907
  - MRLI to WB, ND
  - MRLI to all members; Jan. 8, 1908
  - MRLI Pres. Archibald Haynes to all members; Feb. 31, 1908
  - MRLI Pres. A.H. to all members; ND
  - MRLI monthly receipts and premium notices, Sept. 25, 1900 to Apr. 10, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Business Dealings (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sept. 15, 1835 -Land Grant Certificate to Midad (?) Bordwell
  - Jan. 1, 1843 -Mortgage of Midad Bordwell
  - Apr. 5, 1849 -Warranty Deed (Marriage) between Seth Sylvester and Laura Sylvester, Witnessed by M. Bordwell
  - Nov. 27, 1849 -Indenture of Seth and Laura Sylvester
  - Jan. 1, 1860 -Warranty Deed between Marcus and Mary Brown, witnessed by M. Bordwell
  - Sept. 10, 1860 -Warranty Deed between Philip and Maria Mood, witnessed by M. Bordwell
  - Mar. 13, 1890 -Loan and Trust Company of California Mortgage Bond
  - Dec. 29, 1899 -Certificate of Redemption of Real Estate, purchased by City of L.A.
  - Dec. 21, 1901 -Certificate of Redemption of Real Estate, Purchased by City of L.A.
  - Sept. 24, 1903 -Certificate of Epes Randolf of shares of stock in the Pacific Artificial Limb and Physicians Supply Company
  - Feb. 7, 1907 -Memorandum of transfer of property of WB to Dr. M.N. Avery
  - Feb. 29, 1908 -Guarantors and Investment Co-improvement bond
  - July 17, 1908 -Cancellation of C & I bond 1909 - Assessed valuation on Franchise, Real Estate, and other items
  - Mar. 23, 1911-Mar. 23, 1912 -Columbia Investment Company Statement
  - Mar. 23, 1912-Mar. 23, 1913 -Columbia Investment Company Statement
- Further Personal Finance (receipts IOU's, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - July 1, 1882 -IOU from Eliza Bordwell to WB
  - Apr. 16, 1887 -Promisory note from WB to the National City bank of Marshall, Michigan
  - Apr. 16, 1887 -Promisory note from WB and George Ingersoll to NCB of Marshall, Mich.
  - Aug. 31, 1893 -Check from WB to German American Savings bank
  - Jan. 15, 1894.A.P. Moarse to WB
  - June 1, 1895 -Charge receipt of WB to Farmers' Exchange Bank
  - May 31, 1895 -To J.W.F. Diss, county recorder, From WB
  - Jan. 1, 1898 -IOU from Chas. M. Bordwell to WB
  - Mar. 1, 1898 -IOU from Chas. M. Bordwell to WB
  - Jan. 4, 1913 -Remittance to WB from National Bank of D.O. Mills and Co.
  - Apr. 23, 1913 -Postcard from First National Bank, L.A. to WB
  - June 30, 1913 -Statement from German American Savings Bank, L.A. to WB
  - Oct. 1, 1918 -receipt from Guaranty Trust & Savings Bank to WB
- Income Tax Returns, State of California, City and County of Los Angeles
- Income Tax Returns, City and State & County receipts 1891-1904 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - City and State & County receipts, 1904-1909 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - City and State & County receipts, 1910-1924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - re Tax (correspondence)
    - July 8, 1896 -W.B. Clancy, Riverside County Auditor, to Walter Bordwell
    - May 10, 1917 -Chas. Rudell, deputy, Los Angeles County Tax Collector to WB
- Bank Account Statements
  - Apr. 14, 1910-Apr. 19, 1913
  - Apr. 19, 1913-Apr. 6, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Used check-stub books (Box 3)
    - Feb. 26, 1912-Aug. 19, 1913
    - Aug. 20, 1913-July 1, 1914
    - July 2, 1914-July 15, 1915
    - Jan. 13, 1924-May 22, 1925
    - May 22, 1925-Sept. 23, 1926
  - Cancelled Checks (Box 4)
    - Feb. 1904-May 1916
    - Oct. 1923-Sept. 1926
- Certificates to Practice Law (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oct. 11, 1888 -to practice law in Mich.
  - Nov. 25, 1889 -to practice law in the Southern District of California
  - Oct. 13, 1890 -to practice in California
  - Apr. 7, 1902 -to practice in the Ninth Judicial Circuit Court of the Southern District of Calif.
  - Apr. 10, 1905 -As temporary judge of the Superior court in Los Angeles County
  - Dec. 24, 1906 -as elected judge of the Superior court in Los Angeles County
- Miscellaneous Legal Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nov. 4, 1885 -WB to C.W. Hind
  - Dec. 8, 1890 -C.W. Hind to WB
  - Jan. 27, 1891 -George Ingersoll to WB
  - July 2, 4, 1893 -G. Ingersoll to WB
  - Aug. 25, 1893 -(telegram) H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Aug. 28, 1893 -(telegram) H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Aug. 28, 1893 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Aug. 29, 1893 -(telegram) H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Aug. 31, 1893 -(telegram) H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Aug. 31, 1893 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Sept. 6, 1893 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Sept. 18, 1893 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Jan. 1, 1894 -Snow-Church Co. to John and Weir Co.
  - Sept 20, 1893 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Sept. 20, 1905 -J. J. Petermichel to WB
  - Mar. 21, 1911 -Notice of Sale of real estate at public auction (re John O. Sieh's death)
  - June 13, 1911 -J. Mathews, Chairman, finance Committee, L.A. County Grand Jury to Mr. E.L. Kincaid
  - June 17, 1911 -E.L. Kincaid to L.A. County Grand Jury
  - June 21, 1911 -J.L. Mathews to E.L. Kincaid County Grand Jury
  - Aug. 5, 1911 -E.L. Kincaid to L.A. County Grand Jury
  - Oct. 2, 1914 -receipt of F.A. Patten, att., signed by WB
  - nd -memorandum, Purington case
  - nd -blank memorandum to Barclay, Wilson and Acenter, attorneys at law
- Miscellaneous Legal (transcripts, memoranda, etc.) nd citations (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Justice Reporters' Transcript - amounts collected in justice courts during 1910.
- On return of Execution memorandum
  - Memorandum for defendant; Depositors against savings bank
- Miscellaneous Legal Reports and Booklets (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Jury instructions, NO. 77, 106' City of L.A. vs. A.S. Koyer; Hon. Walter Bordwell, Judge.
  - Opinion of the Court 1911;The People of the State of California vs. Southern Pacific Railroad Company.
  - Ownership of Tide Land; by Bordwell; 1911reprint.
  - Reports and recommendations, re The Oakland Waterfront; by J.T. Flynn (1909).
- Jury lists (and excuses from those unable to serve) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Oct. 9, 1911-
  - Nov. 29, 1911
  - Oct. 9, 1911 -Jury List
  - Oct. 12, 1911 -Jury List
  - Oct. 13, 1911 -Excuse from Dr. John C. Ferbert, M.D., for G.A. Olshausen
  - Oct. 14, 1911 -Excuse from Dr. L.N. Wheider, M.D. for W.C. Williamson
  - Oct. 27, 1911 -Jury List
  - Oct. 27 -List of Excused
  - Oct. 31 -Excuse from W.A. Cundy, M.D., for Byron Lisk
  - nd -Excuse from R.J. Jewell, M.D., for Ben F. Groves
  - Oct. 30, 1911 -Jury List
  - Oct. 31 -Excuse from William V. Cook, M.D., about Charles Stanley
  - Nov. 1, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 3 -Excuse from Henry Prigge, M.D. for C.A. Knapp
  - Nov. 4 -Excuse from Baynard T. Higgens, D.O., for A.W. Ryan
  - Nov. 4 -People unable to serve
  - Nov. 4, 1911 -minutes of examination of venirement upon presentation of their reasons for exemption from jury service
  - Nov.5 -Excuse from Arthur F. Godin, M.D. for B.F. Sanbor
  - Nov. 5 -Excuse from Thomas Davidson, M.D., for James Greenough
  - Nov. 8, 1911 -Jury List (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nov. 8 -Summons of Joseph Hill by Deputy Sheriff of L.A. County, David Miller
  - Nov. 8 -Summons of D.M. Cowen by Deputy Sheriff W.D. Reynolds
  - Nov. 9 -Excuse from O.J. Stafford, M.D., for D.M. Cowen
  - Nov. 9 -Excuse from G.W. Peck, M.D. for D.M. Cowen
  - Nov. 10 -Excuse from M.R. McBurney, M.D., for J.H. Brooks
  - Nov. 13 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 11 -Excuse from Robert Day, M.D., for Chas. Tait
  - Nov 13 -Excuse from A.T. Hembree, M.D., for W.F. Sprinkle
  - Nov. 14 -Excuse from P.G. Gotter, M.D., for J.R. Grant
  - Nov. 14 -Excuse from J.O. Hunt, M.D., for Reuben Shettler
  - Nov. 14 -List of Excused
  - Nov. 15 -Excuse from W.W. Hitchock, M.D., for M.D. Snyder
  - Nov. 15, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 16 -List of Excused
  - Nov. 17, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 16 -Excuse from Dr. E.C. Manning, M.D., for C.M. Wood
  - Nov. 17 -Summons of W.F. Hall by A. Larno, Deputy Sheriff
  - Nov. 17 -Summons of J.H. Clark by P.J. Pirotte, Deputy Sheriff
  - Nov. 17 -Excuse from S. Hunt, M.D., for Joseph Clark
  - Nov. 18 -Excuse from Charles Cowan, M.D., for Thomas Kane
  - Nov. 18 -List of Excused
  - Nov. 19 -Excuse from J.S. Hunt, M.D., for Joseph Clark
  - Nov. 20 -Excuse from John Balsley, M.D., for J.H. Jackson
  - Nov. 18, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 18 -Excuse from F. Dewitt Crawk, M.D., for N.P. Johnson
  - Nov. 18 1911 -Excuse from W.H. Stokes, M.D., for Lewis Landreth
  - Nov. 20 -Excuse from C.W. Bryson, M.D. for F.D. Chipron
  - Nov. 20 -Excuse from Arthur T. Newcomb for G.L. Andrews
  - Nov. 20 -Excuse from W.L. Zuill, M.D. to C.S. Bijington
  - Nov. 22, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 23 -Excuse from J.M. Radebough, M.D., for Frank C. Bolb
  - Nov. 23 -Excuse from T. Hardy Smith, M.D., for G.J. Mitchell
  - Nov. 25 -Excuse from G.D. Jennings, M.D., for J.O. Houser
  - Nov. 27 -Excuse from Chas A. Briggs, M.D., for I.J. Reynolds
  - Nov. 27 -I.J. Reynold's own excuse
  - Nov. 25, 1911 -Jury List
  - Nov. 25, -Summons of F.A. Hilwig by W.D. Reynolds, Deputy Sheriff
  - Nov. 26 -Excuse from E.M. Lazard, M.D., for H.T. Paddock
  - Nov. 27 -Excuse from J. Strothard White for Frank Hulett
  - Nov. 28 -Excuse from Levi D. Johnson, M.D., for Charles Sandorson
  - Nov. 28 -List of Excused
  - Nov. 29, 1911 -Jury List
  - Dec. 1 -List of Excused
- Specific Cases (in which Walter Bordwell was somehow involved). Includes correspondence between attorneys, public reactions, newspaper clippings, etc.
  - Dickey Case (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mar. 24, 1889 -Herbert E. Windsor to WB
    - June 5, 1889 -H.E. Windsor to WB
    - Aug. 18, 1890 -H.E. Windsor to WB
    - Sept. 20, 1890 -H.E. Windsor to WB
    - June 26, 1891 -H.E. Windsor to WB
    - Dec. 17, 1891 -H.E. Windsor to WB
    - Mar. 4, 1892 -Theron F. Giddings, Receiver, National City Bank of Marshall, Michigan, to WB
    - Mar. 8, 1892 -H.E. Windsor to WB
  - Divorce Cases (Nov. 7, 1910- July 13, 1911) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Feb. 4, 1911 -Francis Moody (Sacramento) to WB
      (in re: bills 852 and 853)
    - Feb. 27, 1911 -WB to Hon. Lee C. Gates (L.A.)
      (in re: bills 904 and 904)
    - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to members to the Legislature of the State of California
    - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to members of the State and Assembly (in re: bills 902 and 904)
    - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to Dr. E. Scott Blair (in re: Mrs. Louise Bryant
    - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to Hon. Clyde Bishop (in re: bills 902 and 904)
    - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to Hon. George Freeman (in re: bills 902 and 904)
  - Mar. 20, 1911 -WB to Hon William Kehoe (in re: bills 902 and 904)
  - July 13, 1911 -John Chawner, presiding clerk, and B. Coppack, chairman, of Committee on Marriage and Divorce to WB
  - nd -Anonymous letter to WB concerning divorce
  - Bill A, preliminary draft, and act to amend section 69 of the civil Code and to add two new sections thereto, to be numbered 69A and 69B, relating to the issuance of marriage licenses
  - Assembly Joint Resolution No. 19, proposed by Mr. Hinshaw, Mar. 14, 1911
  - Memorandum on divorce, nd
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Divorce Decree Denied, Sept. 3, 1908,Mrs. Edith G. Haddock vs. James R. Haddock, (2 copies)
    - Divorce Granted Plaintiff, Sept. 22, 1908,Anna R. Scoffield vs. J.V. Scofield
- E.G.B. Dunbar - F. Winstanly Note (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Apr. 6, 1900 -Memorandum of points of propositions made to Mr. Winstanly and Dunbar with reference to $2400 dated Apr. 14, 1896
  - Apr. 14, 1900 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - July 6, 1900 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Oct 6, 1900 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Jan. 7, 1901 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Oct. 5, 1901 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Jan. 6, 1902 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Apr. 22, 1902 -F. Winstanly to WB
  - Jun. 17, 1902 -unreadable, handwritten notes
    (by judge?)
  - Jun. 17, 1902 -receipt, paid by F. Winstanly and E.G.B. Dunbar
  - Feb. 16, 1904 -Acknowledgement of signing IOU to Bank of America from Edith Dunbar
  - Jun. 8, 1909 -IOU from Edith Dunbar to Bank of America
- E.A. Folsom - Thomas D. Satterwhite Note (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Dec. 8, 1902-Aug. 8, 1903 -collection of notes from J.D. Abell to Thomas D. Satterwhite
  - Nov. 19, 1903 -Thomas D. Satterwhite, att., to Bank of Commerce, San Diego, CA
  - Dec/ 15. 1903 -J.L. Bordwell to WB
  - Jan 15, 1904 -W.J. Kirkpatrick to WB
  - Apr. 1, 1904 -W.J. Kirkpatrick to WB
  - Apr. 30, 1904 -W.J. Kirkpatrick to WB w/encl - Apr. 26, 1904 -E.A. Folson to WJK
  - May 7, 1904 -WJK to WN
  - May 10, 1904 -WB to Bank of Commerce, San Diego
  - May 18, 1904 -E.A. Folson to WJK w/encl- May 14, 1904 -IOU from F.A. Folsom to I.A. Lothian
  - May 19, 1904 -WJK to WB wo/encl
- Ferdinand Habl vs. The German American Savings Bank (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - nd -Ferdinand Habl complains and alleges
  - nd -Ferdinand Habl complains and alleges
  - Mar. 1, 1895 -Silvester Stohr to German American Savings Bank w/encl written in German
  - Mar. 26, 1896 -F. Diehm to Mr. C. Ganahl
  - Apr. 7, 1896 -M. Avery to William Whist
  - Apr. 9, 1896 -WB to D. Johnson
  - Apr. 21, 1896 -Silvester Stohr giving power of attorney to Ferdinand Diehm, consul, German American Savings Bank
  - Apr. 30, 1896 -F. Diehm to WB
  - May 21, 1896 -F. Diehm to Mr. C. Ganahl
  - June 16, 1896 -J.A. Riley to WB
  - Aug. 13, 1897 -Ferd. Diehm to WB
  - Aug. 19, 1897 -Ferd Diehm to WB
  - Sept. 18, 1897 -Gottlieb Lederer to German American Savings Bank
  - Dec. 9, 1897 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Dec. 17, 1897 -F. Diehm to WB
  - 1898 -(Inc'd) - Silvester Stohr giving power of attorney to Ferdinand Diehm
  - Jan. 22, 1898 -J.A. Riley, Att, to A.M. Avery, Cashier, German American Savings Bank
  - Feb. 1, 1898 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Mar. 28, 1898 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Apr. 15, 1898 -F. Diehm to WB
  - May 19, 1898 -Assignment by heirs in Austria to Silvester Stohr
  - June 26, 1898 -F. Diehm to WB
  - July 16, 1898 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Aug. 10, 1898 -J.A. Riley to WB
  - Nov. 22, 1898 -Contest of action by Silvester Stohr against Ferdinand Habl
  - Jan. 19, 1899 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Jun. 15, 1899 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Nov. 17, 1899 -F. Diehm to WB
  - Apr. 12, 1901 -J.F. Riley to WB
  - May 18, 1901 -J.F. Riley to WB
  - May 22, 1901 -Affidavit: Ferdinand Habl vs. German American Savings Bank
  - May 27, 1901 -J.F. Riley to WB
  - July 8, 1901 -Agreement between Union Trust and Realty Company and The German American Savings Bank (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Mar. 13, 1906 -WB to Hon. Ferd. Diehm
  - May 20, 1906 -F. Diehm to WB
  - nd -J.U. Dr. Oscar Winternitz, Advocate, Karlsbad to (?) (written in German)
  - nd -J.U. Dr. Oscar Winternitz to (?) (in German)
  - nd -J.U. Dr. Oscar Winternitz to (?) (in German)
  - nd,no name, (in German)
- Haywood Transcripts (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - July 31, 1911 -John D. Works to WB
  - Aug. 5, 1911 -WB to Governor Hawley of Idaho
  - Aug. 7, 1911 -Gov. J.H. Hawley to WB
  - Aug. 14, 1911 -WB to Gov. Hawley
  - Aug. 23, 1911 -Gov. Hawley to WB
  - Oct. 5, 1911 -Hawley, Puckett, and Hawley, Attorneys (Idaho) to Hon. John D. Work, w/encl of Receipt, Oct. 4, 1911
  - Oct. 10, 1911 -John Works, Chairman, U.S. Senate Committee on Expenditures in the War Department to WB
  - Oct. 11, 1911 -WB to John D. Works
  - Oct. 17, 1911 -John Works to WB
  - July 20, 1912 -Sen. John Works to WB
  - July 25, 1912 -WB to John Works
  - July 25, 1912 -WB to James Hawley
  - July 29, 1912 -James Hawley to WB
  - Dec. 14, 1912 -WB to Gov. Hawley
  - Jan. 8, 1914 -John D. Works to WB
  - Jan. 9, 1914 -W.E. Borah to WB
  - Jaun. 13, 1914 -WB to Gov. Hawley
  - Jan. 17, 1914 -WB to Sen. Wm. E. Borah
  - Jan. 17, 1914 -WB to Sen. John D. Works
  - Jan. 21, 1914 -WB to Gov. Hawley
  - Jan. 22, 1914 -John Works to WB
  - Feb. 2, 1914 -James Hawley to WB
  - Feb. 5, 1914 -WB to Sen. John D. Works
- McDonald Tract, Los Angeles County (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sept. 20, 1887 -property of Maria Jesus Dominguez transferred to E.N. McDonald through the Abstract & Title Insurance Company